In this video, we will get an understanding of what is meant by Inline Functions and how it can be applied in Computational Thinking. Inline functions are additional functions which can be input into the Main functions to calculate or convert values within the line of code. Some common inline functions you will be using often would be Inline Lists, Constants, Random and Conversions.
Len(list) returns the number of items in the list, also known as the length of the list. Let’s say that List1 = [0, 1, 2, 3]. Length_of_List1 = len(List1). When the variable, Length_of_List1 is printed, the value 4 will be printed as the output. This is because there are 4 items in the list. Thus, the length of List1 is 4.
Range(start, end) generates a list of integers from start to n - 1 given that end = n. Following the example, List2 = Range(0, 5) will generate a list containing the values from 0 to 4
Range(start, end, step) generates a list of integers from start to n - 1 given that end = n, with a specified step size. Following the example, List2 = Range(0, 5, 2) will generate a list containing the values 0, 2 and 4.
isList(List) returns True if the specified variable is a list and false if it is not. For example, List4 = [ ]. Thus, when isList(List4) is printed, the output will be True.
There are inline constants as well. An example would be  which is written as PI in the Mobius Modeller.Another example would be XY which define a plane at the origin aligned on the XY  axis.
Another example would be XY which define a plane at the origin aligned on the XY  axis.
Inlines can be used to generate random numbers. Rand(min, max) will return a random number in the specific range. For example, if my_number = Rand(0, 2), then the computer will generate a random number between 0 and 2, inclusive of the minimum number but excluding the maximum number. The numbers include decimals as well.
RandInt(min, max) will return a random Integer in the specific range. For example, if my_number = RandInt(0, 2), then the computer will generate a random integer between 0 and 2, inclusive of the minimum number but excluding the maximum number. Thus, the value 0 or 1 will be generated every time the code is executed.
Rand(min, max, seed) will return a random number in the specific range, but the same random number upon every execution of the code.
Inlines can also be used to convert values. This is because some functions only accept radian values, but it is more intuitive to use degrees.
This sums up the video on Inline functions. Next up are some practice questions for your revision. See you next session.